Julius Hobson Papers 001
People's Archive, MLK Library
- Series 16: Personal, 1957-1977
  The series contains personal awards, memorabilia, and materials regarding Hobson's illness and death.
  - Subseries 1: Awards and memorabilia, 1957-1972
    The subseries consists of greeting cards, campaign memorabilia, and two commemorative publications, An Evening to Honor Julius Hobson (1972) and Julius Hobson, A Goad for Change.
    - An Evening to Honor Julius W. Hobson, Undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Julius Hobson, Undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Second Annual Institute on Employment Programs, Undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Malcolm X metal plaque, Undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - License plate and license, Undated (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Greeting cards, Undated (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Buttons and maps, Undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Campaign memorabilia, Undated (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Illness 1972-1977
    The subseries contains letters of sympathy and concern from friends and associates as well as medical files maintained during Hobson's treatment for cancer. Most of the medical files are restricted due to privacy issues.
    - Personal correspondence, Undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence, Undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, Undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Personal correspondence, Undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers, Undated (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Medication Charts, Undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Medication Dosages, Undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Insurance Claims and Nursing Care, Undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Clinic File, Undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Death, 1977-1978
    The series contains condolence messages, a memorial service program, clippings, sympathy cards, and eulogies at the time of Hobson's death in 1977.
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Sympathy Cards, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Statements and Affairs, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - The Julius Hobson Memorial Summer in the Park, Undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Copies of Condolence Messages, Undated (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Copies of Condolence Messages, Undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Memorial service program, Undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, Undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
- Series 18: Biography, 1961-1970
  Most of the subjects in this series are repeated in other series. The items are arranged under issues and organizations important in Hobson's life and appear to have been gathered for general biographical information. Topics include bankruptcy protection for the poor, equal employment opportunity, D.C. desegregation, the D.C. School Board, bus rate hikes, peace, D.C. police, the D.C. freeway fight, CORE, and ACT. Items include D.C. school board charts, clippings, personal letters, interview transcripts, printed publications, reports, and documents produced from Hobson's FOI requests to the FBI (see also Series 13 for other FOI files).
  - Black Pride Manuscript, Undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Book autographed to wife and stepson (2 copies), Undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - David Eaton Interview, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Conversation with Marilyn Robinson, Undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Christopher Jencks Controversy‑Tape and Transcription, Undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - The Beginning of the Struggle, Undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Interview for Washington Round Table, Undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - "Renew American: Hobson the Great Gadfly" (videotaped interview by Marilyn Robinson), 1970s (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - FBI Papers, Undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - FBI/Government Spying, Undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - CSC (Federal Job Discrimination), Undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles after Death, Undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Personal/Family/Awards, Undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Testimonials, Undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Memorials, Undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Jencks Tape, Undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Education, 1967-1971 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Education, 1967-1971 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Publications, 1963 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Television/Radio, 1965-1966 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Biographical, 1964-1969 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Education and School Bd. charts, 1961-1969 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Walter Fauntroy, 1967 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Desegregation DC, 1962-1966 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Education‑Youth Meetings, 1969 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Economic protection (bankruptcy), 1967 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Equal employment opportunity, 1969-1970 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - General Bibliography, 1972-1974 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Disposition of Papers, 1975-1978 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Women's Issues, 1968-1970 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Transportation in DC (Freeway and Rate Hike fights), Undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Peace, Undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Police, Undated (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Race - Civil Rights, 1964-1969 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Race - Civil Rights, 1964-1969 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - CORE, Undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - ACT, Undated (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Housing, Undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
- Series 19: Clippings, 1957-1982
  The series contains clippings about Hobson's activities and issues of concern to him. It also contains a handwritten log of clippings. The clippings are arranged chronologically.
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1960-1967 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1968-1970 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1968-1970 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten log of clippings, Undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
- Series 20: Printed Materials, 1922-1976
  The series contains printed materials, including scholarly and popular journals, court opininons, published books, reprints, and government documents Hobson obtained throughout his life.
  - Subseries 1: Periodicals, 1959-1973
    Contains periodicals arranged by title. Significant items include a 1971 edition of Freedom Ways with selections from Paul Robeson's speeches; 1972-73 editions of Grass Roots, the newspaper of the People's Party; a 1969 article by Hobson on bankruptcy in Government Worker News; and a 1972 edition of Women's Strike for Peace Memo. Periodicals are arranged by title.
    - Administratative Leadership thru Government Workers News, Undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Grass Roots thru Jet, Undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Journal of Negro Education thru The Reporter, Undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Pangolin thru Saturday Review, Undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Society Security Bulletin thru Women Strike for Peace Memo, Undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - The D.C. Gazette, 1971-1972 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - The Capitol Hill Spectator, November 20 1968 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - The Southern Patriot, October 1966 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - The Southern Patriot, March 1970 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Reports, 1961-1970, 1984
    Contains reports from government agencies, non-profits, and individuals. Items are arranged first topically, then by author or title under the subject. The main topics under which reports are arranged include civil rights, the District of Columbia, education, job discrimination, and poverty. There are a number of reports by the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights and Congress leading up to and after the passage of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and on the issue of school desegregation.
    - Alinsky, Undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - A Chronology of Violence and Intimidation in Mississippi since 1961, Undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - CORE, Undated (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - The Day They Marched, 1963 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Martin Luther King: The Search for Justice, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Biography of Martin Luther King, Undated (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Law Center for Constitutional Rights - 1st Annual Report, 1967 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights Under Law 10-Year Report, 1963 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - NAACP - How the National Association for the Advancement of Color People Began, 1914 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - NAACP - Adam Where art Thou?: The NAACP and Adam Clayton Powell, 1963 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - NAACP - Target for 1963: Goals of the Fight for Freedom (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - NAACP - 55th Annual Convention, 1964 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - National Editorial Board of News and Letters - American Civilization on Trial: The Negro as Touchstone of History, May 1963 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - The Negro American in Paperback (2 copies), 1968 (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Paul Robeson memorial service program - Shiloh Baptist Church, April 30 1976 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Socialist Workers Party - The Case for a Black Party, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Upjohn Institute - Civil Rights, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Justice: 1961 Commission on Civil Rights Report (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Hearings Held in Memphis Tennessee, June 25-26 1962 (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Civil Rights: Report of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Reports on Apprenticeship by the Advisory Committees [to the Commission], Undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Civil Rights under Federal Programs: An Analysis of Title VI, January 1965 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Enforcement: A Report on Equal Protection in the South, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Hearings Before the Commission... Vol. I - Voting - held in Jackson MS, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Assassination and Political Violence, October 1969 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - The Mexican American, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Political Participation, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - cycle to nowhere by Paul Good, Undated (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Index: Federal Civil Rights Enforcement Effort, Undated (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Congress - Civil Rights Act, July 2 1964 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Congress - Hearings … regarding the Civil Rights of Persons... Series No. 4 Part II, Undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Congress - Civil Rights: A Staff Report of the Committee on the Judiciary, 1976 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - The Report of a Survey of the Public Schools of D.C., 1949 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Civil Rights in the Nation's Capital: A Report on a Decade of Progress, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Untitled, 1967-1968 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Directory: Board of Education - Administrative and Supervisory Staff, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - D.C. Teachers College - A Report: Seminar on Public School Adult Education, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - D.C. Public Schools - The Guidance Dispatch - Department of Pupil Personnel, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - D.C. Public Schools - Facts and Figures, 1968-1969 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - D.C. Public Schools - Summary Report - A Comprehensive Plan for Public Higher Education in D.C., 1972 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - D.C. City Council - First Annual Report of D.C. City Council, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Advisers on Equal Employment - Equal Employment in the Nation's Capital, Undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - D.C. Citizens for Better Public Education - Toward Better Schools: A Summary of the Passow Report, 1967 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - D.C. Citizens for Better Public Education - Financing the D.C. Public Schools, 1971 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - DCCBPE - A Study of Educational Resource Allocation In A Major Urban School District: The Case of Washington D.C., April 13 1973 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - National Capital Civil Liberties Union - A Police Department in Trouble: Racial Discrimination and Misconduct in the Police Department of Washington D.C., 1968 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - D.C. EEO - Staffing Patterns in the Government of D.C., 1972 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Urban Studies Program - The City is a Classroom by Lawrence Smith et al., 1968 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Congress - Antipoverty in the District of Columbia - Hearing by Task Force on Antipoverty in D.C., March 14 1966 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Congress - A Task Force Study of the Public School System in D.C. As it Relates to the War on Poverty, June 1966 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Congress - Investigation of the Schools and Poverty in D.C. - Hearing by Task Force on Antipoverty in D.C, October,January 1966 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Center for Sociological Research - Jerome Manis - A Study of Migrant Education, 1957 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Intergroup Relations - "Public School Segregation and Integration in the North", 1963 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights - Federally Supported Discrimination, 1961 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture - Economic Factors Influencing Educational Attainments and Aspirations of Farm Youth - 1964, Undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Strategy for Change: A Report on the Model School Division, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - UNESCO - Report on Methods and Means Utilized in Cuba to Eliminate Illiteracy, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - NEA - Second National NEA-PRandR Conference on Civil and Human Rights Education, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - NAACP - Is it Helping Poor Children?, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Responsive Environment Center Program, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Presbyterian Church - An Open Letter: The Public and Its Education, 1969 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Polytechnic High School had a problem, Undated (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Institute of Human Relations - Blueprint for Action: Integration in Education, Undated (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Problems of Segregation and Desegregation of Public Schools, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Public Education: Staff Report, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Federal Rights under School Desegregation Law, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Equal Educational Opportunity in America's Cities: Problems and Programs for Change, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - A Time to Listen - A Time to Act, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Racial Isolation in the Public Schools (Summary and full report), 1967 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights - Schools Can be Desegregated, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Department of HEW - State Curriculum Guides in Science, 1960 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Department of HEW - Effects of Ability Grouping in Schools Related to … Differences in … Motivation, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Department of HEW - Equality of Educational Opportunity, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Congress -, Undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Congress - Books for School and the Treatment of Minorities - Hearings before Ad hoc Subcommittee on De Facto school desegregation, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Congress - A Compilation of Federal Education Laws, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Congress - Hearings before the Select Committee on Equal Educational Opportunity, 1970 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Congress - Equal Educational Opportunity, Parts 1A, 1B, and 2, Undated (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Congress - Desegregation Under Law, Parts 3A and 3B, Undated (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Congress - Inequality in School Finance, Parts 16A, 16B, and 16D-1, Undated (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Congress - Inequality in School Finance, Parts 16D-2 and 18, Undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Congress - A Compendium of Statutes Administered by... Office of Education - Committee on Education and Labor, July 1965 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Congress - Laws Relating to Federal Corrupt Practices and Political Activities, September 1968 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Congress - Congressional Record, 5/5/1975, 6/26/1967 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Congress - Congressional Record Digest, March 15 1963 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Equal Opportunity in Employment: A Call to the Churches., 1966 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Herbert E. Striner 1984 and Beyond: The World of Work (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Herbert E. Striner - Continuing Education as a National Investement, 1972 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission- Study of Minority Group Employment in the Federal Government, 1965-1971 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission - Monthly Report of Federal Employment, October 1967 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission - Conducting Hearings on Employee Appeals, 1968 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission - Monthly report on Federal Participation in Economic and Educational Opportunity Programs, 1968 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - Exploding the Myths: Expanding Employment Opportunities for Career Women, 1966 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - Negro Women in the Population and in the Labor Force, 1967 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - Federal Work Injuries, 1968 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - Federal Work Injury Facts, 1969 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - Employment Outlook for Tomorrow's Jobs, 1968-1969 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Congress - Equal Employment Opportunity Hearings, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Congress - Title 5 - U.S. Code - Government Organization and Employees, 1966 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Congress - Equal Employment Opportunities Enforcement Act Hearings (2 copies), 1969 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Congress - Equal Employment Opportunities Enforcement Act of 1970, Undated (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Congress - Equal Employment Opportunities Enforcement Act of 1971, Undated (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Congress - Migrant Farm Worker in America, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - AFL-CIO - The Southern Labor Story, Undated (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Americans for Democratic Action - A Program for Americans, 1968-1969 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Black Economic Research Center - Report of Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Center for Democratic Institutions - Fund for the Republic - Consumers of Abundance, 1961 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Health and Welfare Council of the National Capital Area - Telling It Like It Is!, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Health and Welfare Council of the National Capital Area - Poverty's Children, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Health and Welfare Council of the National Capital Area - Perspectives on Poverty, 1967 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Edward S. Herman, Undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - A. Philip Randolph Institute - A Freedom Budget for All Americans, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - The Serpent's Wisdom: An Interfaith Multi-Discipline Guide..., 1968 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Upjohn Institute for Employment, Undated (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - University of Maryland School of Social Work - VISTA Training Program, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Congress - 1966 Amendments to the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 - Hearings (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Court Papers, 1967-1970
    Contains primarily court pleadings and decisions in the Hobson v. Hansen and Hobson v. Wilson cases. It also contains some school desegregation cases in other jurisdictions.
    - Hobson v. Hansen - Opinion by Hon. Skelly Wright - U.S. District Court, June 19 1967 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Carl Smuck v. Hobson/Hansen v. Hobson - U.S. Court of Appeals pleadings, 1968-1969 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Hobson v. Gasch - Memorandum for the Respondent in Opposition - Supreme Court of the U.S. - October term, 1966 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Hobson v. Board of Election for D.C., Undated (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Hobson v. Wilson, Undated (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Keyes v. School Dist. No. One, Undated (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Reprints, 1946-1969
    Contains reprints on the subjects of race relations, the black power movement, the civil rights movement, and education. Articles by Saul Alinsky, Franklin Frazier, and August Meier appear in the subseries.
    - American Sociological Review - "Sociological Theory and Race Relations" by Franklin Frazier, June 1947 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Amherst College Alumni News - "The Freedom Riders", August 1961 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Levone Bennett Jr. - "Stockely Carmichael: Architect of Black Power", July 1966 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Freedomways - "The Contours of the 'Black Revolution' in the 1970s" by J.H. O'Dell (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Law Review - "Seniority and Testing Under Fair Employment Laws" by George Cooper and Richard B. Sobol, June 1969 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Journal of Intergroup Relations - "The Successful Sit-Ins in a Border City: A Study in Social Causation" by August Meier, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Negro Education - "The Relationship between Test Intelligence of Third Grade ", Undated (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Negro Children and the Occupations of Their Parents by Mary Robinson and Max Meenes, 1947 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Journal of Negro History - "The Status of the Free Negro in Charleston… and Descendant" by Horace Fitchett, October 1947 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Journal of Social Issues - "The War on Poverty-Political Pornography" by Saul D. Alinsky, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Liberation - "Rifle Squads or the Beloved Community" by A. J. Muste, May 1964 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - The New Republic - "Black Chutzpah" by John Osborne, April 1968 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Monthly Review - "Marxian Socialism: Power Elite or Ruling Class" by Paul Sweezy, 1956 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Rutgers Law Review - "The Constitutional Right of Negro Freedom" by Arthur Kinoy, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Social Forces - "An Analysis of Statistics on Negro Illegitimacy in the United States" by Franklin Frazier, Dec. 1932 (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Social Forces - "Children and Income in Negro Families" by Franklin Frazier, Dec. 1946 (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Southwest Review - "Separate But No Equal: The Sweatt Case" by Charles H. Thompson, 1948 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Triumph - "Betrayal in the Schools" by Martha White Washington, Jan. 1969 (Box 104, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 5: Books, 1922-1976